               MINUTES
                  ...OF THE...
       SECOND CONVENTION 

National Association of Colored Women
                  ...HELD AT...
        ot QUINN CHAPEL, oe
        2,h Strect and Wabash Awn°, 
               CHICAGO, ILL.

          AUGUST 14th, 1St, And i899.

            MINUTES
             ...OF THE...
         SECOND CONVENTION
             -.OF THE...
       National Association of Colored Women,            ...HELD AT...
,            ...HELD AT...
         ,v QUINN CHAPEL, de
          24th Street and Wabash Avenue, 
            CHICAGO, ILL

          AUGUST H. 1511, and 16th, 1899.

  Corresponding Secretary. 
   Recording Secretary. 
    Treasurer. 
   National Organizer. 
 Chairman Executive Committee. 
Chairman Ways and Means Committee.
   /0.1 Committee.

            Monday, August 14th.

Prayer
I ntroil,7,:triidtemarks by the President. Mrs. Mary Church

Delegates Received. 
Credentials Recorded. 
Appointment of Committees.
Reports from °dicers. 
Reports front Delegates.


Reports from Delegates.
Th• 132St Methods of Establishing Schools m Domes,. 
     Science,
          Miss Frances A. Riley, Mod., Pd.
1,neral Discussion Open to all Delegates,
       Led by Mrs Florence Cooper.   rem..

          Mrs,. Lillian C:17:flan, ihdand.


Address of Welcome.
                  CAtillik II II 1lIKISON,
Salutation,
             Nit,. I. .k Davis. Chiedge,
*Item', from the Federation of Colored Women's Clubs of 
     the State of Illinois.
             rs. Connie II. Curl, ///,
RCS,ISC,
       Mrs. Booker 'I' Washington, 7,,,ktger, Aid


          Mrs. Ellen NI. lienrotin, 11/.
Address   the President,
       Mrs. Mary Church Terrell. ll'abiinglon, 
                      Music

            Tuesday, August 15th.


Reports from Delegates.

Discussion of Amendments to the Constitution.




Why the National Associatioh of Colored Women Should
     Devise Means for Establishing Kindergartens.
           Mrs. Haydee Campbell. Se. inn, .1/n. 
Gain!, Discussion Open to all Delegates.
     I,d by Mrs. Ida Joyce Jackson, fejfeeson Cay. Ala.
                        and
           Mrs. Lucy F.. Phillips. pawn, Tenn.



Social Necessity of An Equal Moral Standard for Men 
     a. Women.
       Mrs. Josephine Silone Yates, Kansas 111,
                        Music.
The Child is Father of the Man.
         Mrs. Sylvania I'         Nein Orienns,
One Phase of the Labor Question,
         Mrs. Josephine Bruce. Indionapilis,
                        Music.
Convict Lease System as it Affects Child Nature, 
            Miss Josie E. Holmes, Aganta, Ga.
Lynch Law,
         Mrs. Carrie C. Fortune,      k.   Y.
Prison Work,
         Mrs. Frances Joseph, New On'eams,

    Wednesday, August 16th.




Reports of Standing Committees. 
Election of Officers.




        Miding—Continued. 
Discussion of Resolutions.
General Discussion of the President's Recommendation 
 Respecting the Outline of Work for the Association.

General Discussion on Themes of Reports.



 The Temperance Reform in the Twentieth Century.
    Miss Mary Lynch. ,fisbury. N. C. 
The Relation of the W. C. T. I.'. to the Home,
    Mrs. Lucy Thurman. /dawn. if,.
         M usic.
I,actical Club Work,
   Miss Elizabeth C. Carter,, Palo, Jfa.o. 
The Future Club Work of our Women.
    Mrs. Emma S. Ransom.
Jim Crow Car Law,
   Mrs. Rosa Bowser Branch, Kama., CY, A.ans.
         Music.
Racial Literature,
   M rs. Frances E. W. Harper, PhMidelnhia,

General Information.
The Second Convention,	
First Bienniai of
the National Association	
ore	
be Iteld in 
Qainn Chapel, corner of
Chicago, III., the iath. isth, andAugust.
All sessions are free to the public. The center front of  
the church will be occupied by the members of the Biennial.  
These are the General Officers, the Delegates, anti 
of the organizations belonging to the Association. The re •
t::gseatswitibit'theVTlBadgesn:vornbyal members olorgiZions belonging  
the Association, out by no one else. Badges sill be on sale  
at the Bureau of Information. Quinn Chapel.
It is justly expected that the conferences in which re- 
ports ire
Lite' IT,ww7InItgre'sfeosr	
nenvde4sV.e":1':
that no one will
Th
addresses, or re
of
11 Biennia
mediately upon her arrf  
the 1'resicler.[, directed  
Street and Wabash r\ve  
It is earnestly requt  
. punctual in their at  

cite will nuke
the work of
he c
by t
'hap,
add7s: 
er 	
to
, 
cannot
ru'L
Association
Women, Clubs of th  
August
A Business	
i„
ni.t 17th and twill
N. B — kn address  
livered be "13"1tZ  
• iik. Sunday eve 
the 
ird
he 
red
will be held Thur,day morning, A,•  
during the entire forenoon.
nn Harriet Beecher Stone will be de- 
em in the  
()earborn anti 3ot h Streets, at /:30
to

         MINUTES

           Ot HE

 National Association of Colored Women, 

           1899.


       MONDAY MORNING SESSION.


 A large number of women assembled in 9uinn Chapel. 
corner of 24th St. and Wabash Ave., to be present at the 
opening of the First Biennial Convention of the National 
Association of Colored Women. The meeting was called to 
order by the President, Mrs. Mary Church-Terrell. After 
singing..•Praise God from whom All Blessings Flow." Prayer 
was offered by znd Vice-President, Mrs.Lucy Thurman. A, 
propriate introductory remarks were made by the President. 
The Recording Secretary being absent—detained by illness, 
the first thing in order was the election of the sante. Several 
names were placed in nomination. but as the Committee on 
Credentials had not reported. the President stated that nomi- 
nations and voting were not in order. Mrs. C. A. Curl of 
Chicago was appointed with Mrs. Carrie Williams Clifford of 
Cleveland. /hio, and Miss Lizzie C.C. Carter of New Redford, 
Mass., as assistants.
 The arrangement of scats by States was 11CM. ill order. MI, 
Ruflin of Boston asked what action should be taken concern • 
ing delegates who had not received their credentials and 
others who thought it not necessary to have credential, 
The President decided that Stateorganizers and members of 
the National Association needed no other credentials. All 
others must have their credentials before they could be rec- 
ognized. A short discussion concerning the matter develop. 
ed the fact that the body could not be properly recognized 
until the Committee on Credentials had reported. The Pre,

dent would thus be obliged to make all decisions and ap- 
pointments until the Association was opened in proper form. 
While the credentials werel.ing prepared, Mrs. B. K. Bruce 
asked if persons who were officers of the Association and 
also sent as Delegates would be allowed to east a vote both 
as an officer and delegates. The President informed the 
women that but one vote would be cast by each woman, no 
matter how many positions she might hold. A telegram was 
read by NIrs. S. Lillian Coleman of Omaha, Nebraska, from the 
Rev. C. C. Owens of said city sending greetings and wishing 
for the Association a harmonious and prosperous session. 
Reports from the following Clubs were read by the following 
persons
 I. B. W. Club of Chicago, Mrs. S. Taylor: Woman's Civic 
League, Chicago, Mrs. Minnie Roach; Ideal Club, Chicago, 
Mrs. Ophelia Clark; Women's Era Club. Boston. Mrs. j. St. P.  
Ruffin; Phyllis Wheatly Club. New Orleans, Mrs. Sylvania 
F. Williams; Commercial Reciprocity. Club, Indianapolis, 
Incl., Mrs. Lillian Thomas-Fox; Peoria Woman's Aid, Peoria, 
III Mrs. Sydney Wagoner; Woman's Home Improvement 
Club, Louisville, Ky., Mrs. Fannie B. Williams; Woman's 
Loyal Unions, N. Y. City, Mrs. Imogene Howard; Colterie 
Migratory Assembly, Memphis, Tenn., 'Mrs. Annie Whitlow; 
Sojourner Truth Club. Memphis. Tenn., Mrs. Robert Free- 
man.
 Telegrams of greeting and good wishes were read from 
Mrs. Mary C. 'I'urner of New Orleans and Mrs. M. F. Pitts of  
E. St. Louis, Ill. Mrs. S. G. Snelson. of Athens, Georgia, 
made a report from the Woman's Club of that city. All the 
reports were respectfully listened to and well applauded. At  
the hour of 12, P. M. the Association adjourned to lunch, 
which had been prepared by the ladies of the church, to re- 
assemble promptly at 1:3o P M

              MONDAY AFTERNOON SESSION. 
  The Association reassembled at the appointed time. The 
meeting was called to order by .e President. Mrs. Frances 
Jackson of Kansas Crty read the report of the Committee on 
Credentials. One hundred and forty.four tits) delegates 
were reported. On motion of Mrs. Thurman the delegates

ports. Mrs, Harvey of Mempis. en., reported for the 
Orphan's Horne of ad city mating that twenty•five acres of 
land had been purchased. Others reported as follows: 
  Minerva Club of Cleveland. Ohio. M. W. H Cliffmalt St. 
Lonis Club of Louis, Mo.. Miss Helen Abbott: P. E. Har, 
per League of Pittsburg. Pa.. Mrs. Mattis Mutton who also 
read greetings Nom the King's Daughters of the same city, 
and an invitation inviting the Association to hold its next 
Convention in Pittsbnrg.
  Reports from the Wommes Home and Foreign Mission and 
Educational Club of Mo . read by Mrs. Alice Sumner; Self 
Culture Club, St. Lous. NI0.. Mrs Nellie Gibsom 'Wednesday
Afternoon Club, St. Louis. Silos airs. S. B.   ,TenTimmt
One Chi, Montgomery, Ala,               Ferrier Woman, Pedera•
don of Clubs. Ann ArNor. alias Miss Anna H. Jones. 
  Greetings. from the Genttesnen, Afro.Amerionn Club of 
Pay Citv. Mich , were preaented and read by Ms. Lottie
Jar'      said city. Greetings from the St'omsn's Improve.
meta Club of Detroit, Mich...Imre received through M  Fan•
nie Preston. The discussion of the -Best Methods of Fatah •


the discussion being absent,. President continued to hear 
reports ol clubs. The report from the W. C. T U. Club,
                                Jae
report was.made by Mrs:George Barrier of Detroit. Mich..
                                                 oa
Bruce stated an Inenlent °fa lade huneMback boy living in


Eroa u much coveted prize. Mrs. Lucy Thurman asked

                   10
the President to state the honors which had come to Roscoe 
Brnee, son of Mrs. B. K. Bruce, and the President said in 
part: that while in the school at Exeter he had won all the 
honors, and so he had gone on winning one prize after another 
in all the schools he has attended. lie had lately won at Har- 
vard a medal worth one hundred (Sim.) dollars, called the 
Pasteur Prize.
 A report was then made from the Julia Gaskin Club of 
Evanston, Ill., by Mrs. L. Butler. The President instructed 
the delegates to give the actual amount of monies collected 
and expended by their clubs in making up the final extracts 
to be handed the Chairman of the Press Committee. The re- 
port from the Woman's Improvement Chtb of Knoxville, 
'Penn. was read by Mrs. Jones.
 Mrs, Corine Brown, a woman of great worth who is noted 
for her success as a worker in the city of Chicago, was in- 
vited forward to be introduced to the Association. Mrs. 
Brown in her usual agreeable and winning way made some 
very choice remarks. Among other things she said: that 
she believed that ability depended neither upon race nor 
upon sex. She advised work for legislation, saying the time 
would soon be when the two races would work together, as 
one of us cannot get along without the other. She warned 
those of the Southland to keep their children out of the 
factories before they are years of .1.f,
 Mrs. McDowell who lives in the University of Chicago 
settlements was then presented to the Association. She 
claimed to be a member of the N. A. C. W., as it was she who 
organized the Julia Gaskins Club of Evanston, Ill. She 
advised all to work for the common needs. Miss Farson, 
one of the Superintendents of Chicago schools said that 
she was a delegate on the grounds that the thing you 
long for you are. Her subject was heredity, her remarks 
were logical and interesting. The remarks of all the visi- 
ting ladies were highly appreciated. NIrs. NI. L. Har-
rison St. Louis, Nlo., who is President of the Orphans'
Home. made au interesting report. Mrs Lillian Cole- 
man •of Omaha, Nebraska, was called upon (she being 
the only one present who had been placed upon the pro-

                       11
gram, to open the discus "Best Methods of Establish-
ing Schools of Domestic Science." Mrs. Coleman read a 
beautiful and instructive paper, which was listened to with 
profound silence. The inspiring paper had its effect and 
many of the delegates took part in the discussion. Mrs. L. 
Anthony read the names of the Ways and Means Committee 
and requested them to meet immediately after adjournment. 
On motion of Mrs. L. A. Davis the Convention adjourned 
until 8 o'clock P. M., when they were entertained ac a reccp• 
lion given under the leadership of Mrs. Dr. Carey. Business 
Session to begin Tuesday morning at the usual hour,

         TUESDAY MORNING, AUGUST 15th, 1899.
  The First Biennial Convention of the N. A. of C. W. was 
called to order by the President at to o'clock A. M. The 
names of the following committees were announced on cour- 
tesies:
  Resolutions and minutes read and approved: after which 
prayer was offered by Mrs Lucy Thurman, and the Conven- 
tion was declared open for the regular business. The min- 
utes of the first day's session were read and approved after 
adding the name of Nliss Carter of New Bedford to those of 
the Committee on Resolutions. The reports of the clubs were 
called for in the following order: Waytnen Circle, Mrs. Nora 
Taylor. Chicago, 111, Phyllis Wheatley, Mrs, M. B. Jackson, 
Chicago. The printed address on "The Progress of Colored 
Women," delivered at the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Na- 
tional American Woman's Suffrage, delivered by Mrs. Terrell 
was offered for sale at to cents each. Mrs. Terrell offered to 
donate the proceeds to the Association, provided the money- 
should be used only for the support of Kindergartens and 
Day Nurseries. Quite a number were disposed of.
  Mrs. Lucy Thurman moved that Wednesday morning, at 
it o'clock. the election of officers take place. Motion carried. 
The reports of clubs were then continued as follows: North 
Omaha Woman's Club, Miss Gamble: Phyllis Wheatley Club, 
Nashville, Tenn., Mrs, Shelton: Progressive Circle of King's 
Daughters, Chicago, Ill.. NIrs. Birdie Evans. The amend• 
menu to the constitution were next considered. On motion

              12
of the Secretary it was decided to limit the time of each 
speaker to three minutes, and no one should be allowed to 
speak twice on the same article until all who desired to speak 
had spoken. Article 3. section 3, to read a per capita tax, to 
be fixed by the Convention. Mrs. Thurman moved the amend- 
ment that a per capita tax of co cents annually should be paid 
by each member of the several clubs: after many had spoken 
and all in favor of the per capita tax, the motion prevailed. 
 Article 4 was amended so as to read: a National Organizer, 
who shall compose the Executive Board. After much dis- 
cussion both pro and con, Mrs. Thurman moved the previous 
question; motion carried. A vote was then taken with the 
result that the amendment was unanimously lost. Article 4, 
Section 1, be changed to read after the words written ballot: 
a majority of votes shall be necessary to a choice; the motion 
was lost. Article„ Section 2, be amended to read as it is 
written with the omission of the last three lines. Mrs. 
Washington moved its adoption; after much dissension Mrs. 
Anthony moved the previous question; motion carried. The 
Article was then re-read as amended and unanimously car- 
ried. An amendment to the Constitution was then read as 
follows; the Recording Secretary shall perform such duties 
as are USIIili to hcr °ince and receive and receipt for all funds 
received by her and promptly turn the same over to the 
Treasurer. Mrs. Williams of New Orleans moved this Art- 
icle be adopted; motion carried It was found necessaay to 
change Section 3, Article 3, to read: through the Recording 
Secretary, and thus clo away with the new amendment. Mrs. 
Thurman moved the new amendment be stricken out: motion 
carried. Miss Carter of New Bedford, Mass., moved that 
Section I. Article 5, be so amended as to cover the ground: 
motion carried. Mrs. Williams moved we expunge Section 
2, Article 5, from the Constitution; motion carried, (as it was 
needed). Section 3, Article 5, strike out Corresponding Sec- 
retary: on motion of Mrs. Williams of New Orleans it was 
carried. Article 5, Section 5, was amended to read after the 
words, at a time: she shad hold her office for an unlimited 
time; yeas 66, nays 5o; in ition to amend lost. Section 3, 
Article 5, amended to read: all past of of the National

                      13 
       Association shall be entitled to membership; motion lost. 
       Association adjourned at 2,5 P. M., to reassemble at 3 P. NI.


               TUESDAY AFTERNOON SESSION.
        At 3, P. If. the Convention reassembled. Prayer was 
       offered by Mrs. Barber, National Treasurer of the W0111211, 
       Christian Temperance Union. Mrs. Ruffin reported that 
       one of the delegates had lost her pocket-book which con- 
       mined her ticket and all her money; she was also sick and had 
       to incur a doctor's expenses since her misfortune. A small 
       donation was asked for her and the President allowed a col- 
       lection to be lifted. 'rhe name of said delegate was held in 
       reserve. Ten ($10.00) dollars was donated. Jigs. Haydee 
       Campbell of St. Louis, Nfo. was called and introduced to the 
•      Association. Her subject was: "Why the National Associa- 
       tion should devise means to establish Kindergartens.- Too 
       much cannot be said of the paper. To say it was carefully 
       prepared and well read, are feeble words. Mrs. Ida J. Jackson 
       of Jefferson City, Mo., was introduced and opened the discus• 
       sion by reading a paper. It was a masterly production, and, 
       like others, was heartily applauded. Mrs. Lucy E. Phillips 
       of Jackson. Tenn., came next and her paper was equal to the 
       others. The subject was then open to all the delegates for 
       general discussion. A recess was taken while the R. R. Agent. 
       attended to signing certificates. The women were instructed 
       to have their certificates at the Bethel A. M. E. Church to be 
       signed. The Committees were instructed to meet at 3 o'clock 
.      sharp. Wednesday morning. Mrs. Will was present and
       spoke in the interest of the Kindergarten. She advised
       working through the Legislatures of states and in that way
       have Kindergartens established, A motion to adjourn was
       carried, and the Association adjourned to reassemble at 8
       o'clock P. NI. Wednesday.

                 TUESDAY EVENING. 
        At nine ,clock the Convention was called to order. Prayer 
       was offered by Rev. Richard Cole of St. Louis, Nfo., after 
       which the regular programme of the evening was begun.

               I4
The church was packed to its utmost capacity, and the pro• 
gramme throughout was respectfully listened to. Several 
distinguished guests were present and were invited by the 
President to seats upon the platform. Among whom were 
Bishop Turner, Booker T. Washington and Edward Brown 
of Boston, Afass. With few exceptions the programme was 
carried out as arranged. Mrs. Carrie C. Fortune of New 
York and Mrs. Frances Joseph of New Orleans. being absent, 
Airs. Ruffin read a paper and Mr. Brown of Boston made 
stirring remarks concerning the Lynch Law, and read reso- 
lutions which he asked all to endorse. The Convention then 
adjourned to reassemble at the usual time and place Wedne, 
day morning.
             Alaiiv CHURCH•TrtikEl.t.,
           Ali, CONNIE C. Cy..,
     WEDN.DAY MORNING, AUGUST 16th. 1899.
 The Convention was called to order at 9:•0 by the Presi• 
dent; prayer was offered by Mrs. Brown of Ohioand the meet- 
ing declared open for the regular business. Minutes of the 
previous day were read and approved. On motion of Mrs. 
Thurman the report of officers was called for while the A, 
sociation was waiting. in the absence of Mrs. J, S. Yates, 
Miss Carter of New Bedford, Mass., made a verbal report for 
the N. E. Federation of Women, Clubs of New England and 
New York States; 27 clubs were reported by her. Next was a 
report from the Woman's Conference read by Mrs. Fannie B. 
Williams of Chicago. Mrs. Ida B. Barnett, being. the house. 
was invited to a seat upon the platform. Her time being limit• 
ed, she requested to make two announcements as follows: 
that the Afro•American Council would convene in Chicago. 
Thursday morning, at Bethel A. M. B. Church, to which all 
were invited. She then extended an invitation from Miss 
Jane. Adams of the Hull House to have the officers of the 
Association visit her home and have luncheon with her. 
The invitations were graciously accepted. Airs. Barnett then 
retired On private business. Greetings were read by the 
Secretary from the Lend-a-Hand Circle of Boston. Report 
from Atlanta Woman's tlub was read by Mrs. Ioste E. Holmes. 
On motion of Mrs. F Jackson the . 'ation then went in-

                15
to Executive Session and all visitors were excused from 
the room. The reports of officers were deferred until the 
afternoon session. Before going into the election it was 
suggested to better tit us for the ordeal and solemnize our 
hearts, five prayers be offered in five minutes, which was 
accordingly done and while a feeling of solemnity pervaded 
the house, the following names were placed in nomination 
for President Mesdames Bruce, Washington, Ruffin, Yates, 
Thurman and Terrell. It had been fully understood that as 
the present President had served but one term since the law 
of two terms had gone into effect, she was eligible to a re- 
election. Sitich discussion was indulged in on all subjects 
pertaining to balloting, and after much time had been c.• 
sinned, on motion of Sirs. Anthony those who desired to do 
so were told they might withdraw their names. After more 
thought and discussion their names were continued and the 
balloting begun. Sirs. Ruffin moved that as the name of each 
delegate was called, she should come forward and deposit 
her vote on the table in front of the Convention. Motion 
carried. The balloting was quietly conducted and resulted 
in the re-election of Mrs_ Mary Church Terrell as President 
for the ensuing term, she receiving ioO votes of the i44 
cast on the first ballot. The hour being far past noon Sirs. 
Bruce moved that we adjourn to lunch and rest until 
P. Si, Motion was unanimously carried. Lunch had been 
prepared by the ladies of the church as usual.

         WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON. 
  At    NI., the President sounded the gavel and the 
Convention was reassembled. Sirs. Bruce read greetings 
from Sirs. Rosetta E. Lawson. of Washington. D. C. A tele- 
gram from Sirs. Julia Hooks concerning little Lucy Russell, 
of Memphis. Tenn, was read. She sent greetings and dues. 
'rite balloting was then resumed. Mrs. Anna Jones, of 
Kansas City moved that the rules be suspended and the offi- 
cers be as they then stood. 1. motion was lost and 
the regular way of voting was the order. The following names 
were placed in nomination for First Vice President: Me,

               16
dames Ruffin, Anthony and Bruce. Mesdames Ruffin and 
Anthony withdrew. Mrs. Moody moved the rules be sus- 
pended and Mrs. Bruce be elected by acclamation. Motion 
elrried. Second Vice Presidents were nominated as fol• 
lows: Mesdames Coleman of Nebraska. Thurman and Mrs. 
Lucy Phillips. After the first ballot the name of Mrs. Cole- 
man was dropped, she having the least number of votes, 
and on the second ballot which stood 69 and 7o for the can- 
didates Mrs. Thurman withdrew and Mrs. Lucy E. Phillips. 
of Jackson, Tenn., was declared elected. The following 
names were placed in nomination for Corresponding Sec- 
retary: Miss Mary Lynch, of N. C., Mrs. Fannie 13. Williams, 
of Chicago, Miss Anna V. Thompkins of Washington. D. C. 
Miss Mary Lynch was elected. Most of the afternoon was 
spent in electing a Recording Secretary. Since it is always 
necessary to appoint two assistants to the Recording Secre• 
tart', it was deemed wise to elect three recording secretaries 
instead of one. The following names were balloted upon 
with the following result: Mrs. C. A. Curl of Chicago, Miss 
L. C. Carter of ,ew Bedford, Mass., Mrs. Sutton of Pittsburg. 
First elected was Mrs. C. A. Curl, who received too votes, 
second, Mrs. Coleman of Nebraska was elected by aeelama- 
tion, and third, Mrs. Carrie Will Clifford of Cleveland was 
elected. On motion of Mrs. Anthony the rules were sus- 
pended and Mrs. Silo. Yates was unanimously re-elected 
Treasurer. By acclamation and on motion of Mrs. L. A. 
Davis, Mrs. Jeffries, National Organizer was re•elected in the 
same way. Mrs. Bruce nominated Mrs. Booker T. Wash• 
ington as Chairman of the Executive Committee. She was 
also elected unanimously by acclamation. During the after- 
noon Mrs. Louie Jackson of Bay City took every imprint, 
nity to impress upon all the necessity of subscribing for the 
official organ of the Association. The notes $tS.00 in sub- 
scription was secured. Many of the books offered by Mrs. 
Terrell for sale in interest of a Kindergarten were sold; $38 
was realized. Rev. and Mrs. Carey were called for to come 
forward that they might receive the thanks of the Association 
for their many kindnesses in allowing the use of so beauti- 
ful a church for the Convention: its conveniences and

              17
splendid ventilation added much to the comfort of the As- 
soeiation. Rev. Carey responded, and after being thanked 
by the President in behalf of the Association made some 
beautiful remarks, complimenting women& work and women 
in general. The Association then adjourned until 8 o'clock 
when the regular program was carried out. After the first 
hour, which was given the W. C. T. U., led by Mrs. Lucy 
Thurman, Mrs. Amanda Smith, Bishop Turner and other 
noted persons took part.

     THURSDAY MORNING, AUGUST I7th,
 The Convention was called to order at to:45 A. NI., and was 
opened by singing and prayer. Nlinutes of the last session 
read and adopted. Mrs. J. S. Yates, Treasurer of the Associa. 
lion, made her report. (See special reports). Report from Com- 
mittee on Ways and deans was also read by Mrs. J. S. Yates. 
(See reports). On motion of Mrs. Aldrich the report was 
approved. The Corresponding Secretary, Ntiss A. V. Thom, 
kins read her report; on motion of Mrs. Moody it was approved. 
Mrs. Agnes Moody then introduced to the Convention Miss 
Hattie Johnson, a young colored woman, clerk in Siegel and 
Cooper's large department store ■-,1 Chicago. She was cor- 
dially greeted by the Association. Ales. Lyles of Minnesota, 
made an earnest plea in behalf of the proposed John Brown 
Monument for which the sum five thousand nine hundred 
($5.9o, dollars has been raised already. Ales. Jones of St. 
Louis, Mu, read the report of the Committee on Resolutions 
(See report), which was adopted singly as follows:
 Resolution No. t, adopted on motion of Ntrs. Aldridge.
           •. •.    Sirs. Hatton.

                   " M r[8s.tNi.„1:',:vkost7].
         4.        • Airs. J. Q. Oran,.
         5.         Mrs. Bowser,

         6           ilst\')'711ii:Firotfe.
                    [North Carolina.]
                    NIrs. A. Douglas.
                   " Mrs. Aldridge,
                    Mrs. B. A. Town.
send. " 


                          18

  Section to comprised sections, which On motion was in• 
dorsed. Mrs. Fannie Preston suggested that the resolution 
presented by Mr. Brown of Boston be inserted as Afro•Anier- 
lean Council resolution. (See resolutions.) Mrs. Cooper 
suggested that a stronger resolution be drawn up by the 
Association. Mrs. McCoy moved the resolution of Mr.Brown 
be adopted as resolution No. t t. Motion carried. Resolu- 
tion No, 12 adopted on motion of Mrs. Fannie Preston. Mrs. 
Smith of the Ideal Club moved that No. t3 be laid on the 
table but withdrew the motion. .

             THURSDAY AFTERNOON SESSION.
  Mrs... K. Bruce offered the following resolution which 
took the precedence of the former : •That the N. A. C. W• 
now assembled extend greetings to the A. A. C. and ex' 
press our sympathies with, and indorsement of the pur- 
poses of the organization.• On motion of Mrs. McCoy it was 
adopted with the amendment that a Committee of five be 
appointed to bear the same to the Council then in session. 
  Resolution No was, on motion of Miss Fannie Preston 
adopted. Resolution N. 15, extending thanks to Chicago 
was adopted with the amendments of Mrs. Bruce and Mrs. 
Thurman: 1st—that special thanks be extended the Pastor 
and wife; end—to include the janitor with a donation: the 
latter received a standing vote and a voluntary collection 
was taken.
  Mrs. Cooper said Convention should not adjourn until 
so:nc   (3,1 was taken upon the action of .Mrs. Harris. It

  Un motion '"IcInr's74,enre.s Moody thanks were extended the

PrOn motion of Mrs. Day of Kansas City the resolutions as a 
whole with the few corrections otTered. were adopted.
  The Convention then adjourned to reassemble in Execu. 
tive Session Friday morning to finish up the business.
  The officers had been invited by Miss _lane Addams of the 
Hull House to visit a. to lunch. Led by ,Mrs. Ida B. Wells- 
Barnett, they accordingly went forth at P. M.
  For final. see Minutes., Executive Session.
                    Mrs. Mary Church-Terrell. President. 
                    Mrs. C. A. Curl. Ree. See. Pin ten,

           Officers 1899.1901.



                Presiden t . 
Mas ?dm, Citescu•Tatesst., 326 T St„ N. %V_ Washington. D. C.

               First Vice President.


           Second Vice President.


             Recording Secretaries. 
     Mx, C. A. 293S Armour Ave.. Chicago. 111.
     Mx, CA.. W. C1.111... Ckveland, Ohio.

                Treasurer.

             National Organizer.


         Chairmau Executive Committee. 


      Chairman Ways and Means Committee. 


           Corresponding Secretary.

     EXECUTIVE SESSION.

       MONDAY, AUGUST 14TH.
The Executive Cominitee called to order at Quinn Chapel 
at 8.3o A: M., Mrs. B. T. Washington in the chair.
It WAS moved and seconded that the Executive hold 
daily meetings (subject to the call of the chairman) for the 
'consideration of business. Carried. It was moved and 
seconded we recommend that the month of July be the time 
of the National Meeting subject to change if necessary. 
Carried.
It was moved and seconded that Mrs..Thurman be made 
chairman of the symposium, to be allowed the time given 
by the temperance women. Carried.
Mrs. Ruffin to be given the time allotted on the program 
to Mrs. Francis Joseph.
It was moved and seconded that the clubs in the National 
send the name and address of their respective presidents to  
the Chairman of the Executive Committee immediately upon 
their election. Carried.
An improvement on the balloting was discussed but noth- 
ing decided. To be taken up later.
The question of furnishing transportation for the National 
and State Organizers was discussed. The deficiency in the 
financial plan of our organization discussed. Equal repre• 
sensation discussed, Delegates according to numbers re• 
commended.
The plan of being recognized in the National body by 
State organization rather than by individual clubs as at 
present decided.
Adjourned.

       THURSDAY, AUGUST OTH.

Meeting opened. Mrs. Washington in chair.
The question of reorganizing the executive committee 
was discussed. It was decided that in case of a crisis. the  
President take the initiative and Make the decision by which 
the body abide.

           21
 It was moved and seconded that all state organizers be re- 
tained as at present. if satisfactory to the delegation. Carried 
 It was moved and seconded by Mrs. Thurman that the 
organization allow their National Organizer the sum of 
One Hundred (Stoo.00) with which to carry on her work for 
two years to be paid quarterly. This precipitated a general 
discussion. Motion carried.
 It was moved and seconded that the sum of $53.X, that 
went over from the old Federation before the Union was 
effected, be applied to the printing of the minutes of the 
meeting held at Washington. Carried.
 A letter from Mrs. Handy bearing on the monies turned 
over by her to t. Association was read and discussed.
 It was moved and seconded that the N. A. C. W. join the 
National Council of Women. Carried.
 The plan of raising money necessary to become members 
of the Council was discussed.
 It was moved and seconded that we appoint from the Ex- 
ecutive Board zo members to make themselves responsible 
for $, each to be turned over to the Treasurer before Janu- 
ary ist, iocio. Carried.
 The Executive Board let, that matter to the Chairman of 
the Executive Board.
 It was moved and seconded that the minutes of this Con- 
vention be printed Carried.
 It was moved and seconded that Mrs. Ruffin be appointed 
Chairman on Printing, three in number whom she shall 
select_ Carried.
 Mrs. Florence J. Hunt mentioned by Miss Lynch as State 
Organizer for North Carolina.
 Mrs. Bruce suggested Mrs. Lillian Thomas Fox for Indiana. 
 Mrs. Washington—NIrs. Lhingee for Alabama.
 Mrs Jackson—Mrs. I.. Harrison of Missouri.
 rs. Charlotte J. Hunt, Riddell University. Charlotte, N. C. 
 Mrs. Lillian Coleman-•the name, Anna E.Roler,Nebraska. 
 Mrs Jeffries suggested 'Miss Garner for New York
 Mrs. C W. Clifford suggest. Mrs. Harriet K. Price of Ohio. 
 NIrs. Phillips offered Mrs. A. S. Joncs—Tennessee.
 Meeting adjourned to meet Friday morning, at o'oclock in 
the parlors of the Bethel Church.





     ----1111=1111111.i

               FRIDAY, AUGUST laTH.
  Meeting called to order, Mrs. Thurman in the chair. it 
was moved and seconded that State Presidents become mem- 
hers of the National Executive. Carried.
  Mrs. Coale Wilson Jackson spoke on the action taken in 
reference to the separate coach law and mentioned the atti• 
tilde taken by Elizabeth Cady Stanton in the National Con- 
vention!of Woman Suffragists. She also read a letter written 
by her to the Woman's Journal. It was moved and seconded 
that we end.irse the work by Mrs. Jackson in connect,n 
with the separate coach law and that we give her our hear, 
support. Carried.
  It was decided that all money orders be made payable to 
the Treasurer but mailed to the Recording Secretary. who 
;hall receipt to the club sending the order, and the Treas- 
urer shall receipt to the Recording Secretary.
  All p:rsoas holding bills against the Association were re- 
tested to hind them in so that the Treasurer could settle 
all claims and begin the new term with a clean record.
  It was moved and seconded that the N. A. C. W. should ac- 
•ept with thanks the acres of land donated by Flarriet 
Tubman, if they were unencumbered. Withdrawn.
  It was moved .d seconded that a Committee on liteor• 
poration be appointed. Motion carried.
  It was moved and seconded that the,. A. C. W. send a 
printed appeal to the School Boards throughout the States 
to introduce kindergartens and manual training schools into 
the public school system, where they do not now exist; said 
petition to be signed by the President and Secretary. Motion 
arried. It was moved and seconded that a Committee of 
three be appointed by the Chairman-Presiding of the House 
to frame this appeal.
  Committee.—Mrs. Nlary Church-Terrell, Chairman: Miss 
Thompkins and .Mrs. Silvania Williams
  It was suggested that the ladies in their respective locali- 
ties impress upon their young women the possibilities open- 
: ag before them in the field of becoming trained nurses. 
  It was moved and seconded that the matter of time and 
place for the next Biennial be in t decided at this time_ 
Motion carried.

            za
 An invitation extended to come to St. Louis, Mo. with- 
drawn.
 An invitation extended to come to Alanta,
 An invitation extended to come to Indianapolis, Ind. 
 An invitation extended to come to :Minnesota.
 An Invitation extended by the North Eastern Federation 
to meet in New York.
 An invitation extended to come to Michigan.
 Mrs. NfeCoy of Detroit was introduced as the woman who 
was the mother of the idea of organizing into a National body. 
 There was a general discussion about the place of meeting. 
 it was suggested that the Excutive Board meet in l000 
when t. program for tool he made out.
 It was moved and seconded that a regular Program Coin• 
mittee be today appointed to make out our next Program. 
Motion carried.
 The reacting of the Minutes of the Executive Session in 
Washington in ISO was called for. Read by Miss Thompk ins. 
 It was moved and seconded that with the necessary cor• 
rections they be adopted. Motion carried. Hera followed a 
long discussion.
 It was moved and seconded that the Program Committee be 
nothinated from the floor and elected. Motion carried. 
 Candidates Mrs. Washington. Chairman; NIrs. Terrell, 
:Miss Carter, Mrs. E. P. Ensley. Secretary: and Mrs. Aldridge  
Pitts.
 Mrs. Terrell requested that it be the sense of this meet• 
ing that she see the minutes of this meeting, before they go 
into the hands of the Printing Committee.
 Mrs. St. l' Ruffin demanded that the minutes be sent 
direct to her from the Recording Secretary
 It was moved and seconded that the three Secretaries and 
the President of the Executive Board get together and con• 
fer and correct them before the Recording Secretary send 
them to the Printing Committee. Motion carried.
 it was decided that we incorporate in the minutes of the 
N. A. C. W. such part of these minutes as shall be of interest 
to the public.

 It was decided that whenever the Executive Committee 
met the body could appoint its own Secretary as they came 
together.
 It has been moved that this body appropriate $1o.00 to be 
given into the Treasury of the Quinn Chapel in which our 
meetings were held. Motion carried.
 It was suggested that at every Session of the Convention 
the baskets be passed hereafter

































